<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on KubeFleet</title><link>https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on KubeFleet</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started with Fleet using KinD clusters</title><link>https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/kind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/kind/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this tutorial, you will try Fleet out using
&lt;a href="https://kind.sigs.k8s.io/">KinD&lt;/a> clusters, which are Kubernetes clusters running on your own
local machine via &lt;a href="https://docker.com">Docker&lt;/a> containers. This is the easiest way
to get started with Fleet, which can help you understand how Fleet simiplify the day-to-day multi-cluster management experience with very little setup needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;p>kind is a tool for setting up a Kubernetes environment for experimental purposes;
some instructions below for running Fleet in the kind environment may not apply to other
environments, and there might also be some minor differences in the Fleet
experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with Fleet using on-premises clusters</title><link>https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/on-prem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/on-prem/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this tutorial, you will try Fleet out using a few of your own Kubernetes clusters; Fleet can
help you manage workloads seamlessly across these clusters, greatly simplifying the experience
of day-to-day Kubernetes management.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Note&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tutorial assumes that you have some experience of performing administrative tasks for
Kubernetes clusters. If you are just gettings started with Kubernetes, or do not have much
experience of setting up a Kubernetes cluster, it is recommended that you follow the
&lt;a href="https://kubefleet.dev/docs/getting-started/kind/">Getting started with Fleet using Kind clusters&lt;/a> tutorial instead.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>